Guide to the Robert B. Textor Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert B. Textor papers
circa 1964-2011
SC1190
Textor, Robert B.
5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use. Audio-visual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Preview of F983 Austria, 2005; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD-ROM) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Word Future Society's 6th General Assembly 89398-M4014 Ethnographic Futures Research, Undated; 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - A Guide to EFR Master Copy, Undated; 1 video reel(s) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Inst. Fin. Gov. -- Weiler-Levin, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - EFOC Habit Front, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - EFR Hdbk Rewrite Ch 1, 1987 Jul 5 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - EFR Hdbk Rewrite Ch 3, 1987 Jul 5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - EFR Hdbk Rewrite Ch 2, 1987 Jul 5 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Futs Biblio - Textor, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - EFRs Froldwer Ty Prac Instructional Mays, 2008 Jul (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - EFRS Practicum 01., 2008 Aug 11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - EFRS Practicum 01. Participants, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - SU Traffic Safety, 1987 Feb 20 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - White, Morgan, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - EFC Training Tape, 1979 Jan (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Practicum Rimd Conducting, 2008 Jul 30 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Charts EFC, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Antic Anth - Ideas, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Riner, Reed, Undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - (not labeled) A Note of the Introduction to the Student's Edition of the Handbook, 1989 Jan 19 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - EMRC Nuggets, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Anticipatory Anthropology and the Telemicroelectronic Revolution: A Preliminary Report From Silicon Valley, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Anth 269/Educ 287 Alt. Futures, 1979 Jan. 8 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The natural Partnership Between Ethnographic Futures Research and Futures Education, 1979 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cultural Approaches to Alternative Futures Memo 1, 1979 Jan. 8 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Cultural Approaches to Alternative Futures Memo 2, 1979 Jan. 8 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Presentation of Training Videotape on Ethnographic Futures Research, 1979 Jan. 14 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The Natural Partnership Between Ethnographic Futures Research and Futures Education, 1979 Feb. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - RBT to EFR handbook File, 1980 Nov. 24 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Ethnographic Futures Research As a Tool for Educational Diagnostics: A Brazilian Case Study, 1979 Sept. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Venue of EFR Interview, 1979 Sept. 15 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - The File of the "Handbook on EFR", 1979 Sept. 21 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - EFR Publications Files, 1979 Sept. 17 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Jack Alpert's Reactions to the E.F. Interviewing Format, 1978 June 12 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Debriefing of Cultural Futuristics Meeting, 1978 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Futures Research and Social Cassation, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Compensation for Lecturing to ASEAN Scholars, 1980 Dec. 11 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Debriefing of May 15 Cultural Futuriastics Meeting, 1978 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Final Copy of ASEAN Scholars Report, 1980 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Alternative Futures for ASEAN: An Educational Perspective, 1980 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - CF/EFR, 1980 July (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Cultural & Educational Futures Flyer, undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Alternative Futures for ASEAN: An Educational Perspective, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - The Biotechnical Revolution and Alternative Sociocultural Futures for Austria: Some Key Policy Questions, 1985 Dec. 18 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Anticipatory Anthropology, 1985 Aug. 31 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - A Handbook on Ethnographic Futures Research First Edition: Version B, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Anticipatory Anthropology and the telemicroelectronic Revolution: A Preliminary Report from Silicon Valley, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "Alternative Sociocultural Futures for Thailand", 1988 May 27 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - For EFR Handbook Re-Write, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Technolgie und soziale Kontrolle, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Conference, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Educational Value of EFR, 1978 Dec. 18 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Final Report on Chiang Mai University-Ethnographic Futures Research Project, 1981 Dec. 15 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - ADAM, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - A Handbook on Ethnographic Futures Research First Edition: Version B, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - A Handbook on Ethnographic Futures Research First Edition: Version A, 1980; 1 computer file(s) (PDF)
  - Biotechnology and Alternative Sociocultural Futures for the World, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Smithsonian Nuggets, 1983 Dec. 6 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Ethnographic Futures Research, undated (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Cultural Futures Research, Winter 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Cultural Futures Research, 1983 Autumn (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Alternative Futures for ASEAN: An Educational Perspective, 1980 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Open Forum, undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Application for Funds to Write Book on Anticipatory Anthropology, 1982 Sept. 23 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Scenario Methodologies and Your Article in Cultural and Educational Futures, 1979 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - AA Ch. 7, Ch. 8, 1985 March 3 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Anticipatory Anthropology and the Telemicroelectronic Revolution: A Preliminary Report from Silicon Valley, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Thailand Futures Protocol, 1977, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Council on Anthropology and Education (2 copies), 1977 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Cultural futures for Thailand: An Ethnographic Inquiry, 1978 Oct. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Ethnographic Futuristics and the Future of Southeast Asian Studies, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Silicon Images: An Assessment of the Future Cultural Implications of the Computer Revolution, 1981 Nov. 4 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Ethnographic Futures research As a Tool for Educational Diagnostics: A Brazilian Case Study (2 copies), 1979 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Ethnographic Futures Research and Its Educational Potential, 1978 Oct. 20-22 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - The Natural Partnership Between Ethnographic Futures Research and Futures Education (2 copies), 1979 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Ethnographic Futuristics and the Future of Southeast Asian Studies, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Taming the Shrewd: Computer Networks and Human Values, undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Alternative Futures for ASEAN: An Educational Perspective, 1980 July 10 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - EFR Interview, 1989 March 19 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Alternative Sociocultural Futures for Stanford: A Pilot Inquiry of the University Community, 1987 Sept. 30 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - A Handbook on Ethnographic Futures Research First Edition: Version A, 1980 Jan. 23 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Preface/Table of C./Chpt. 1, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - AA05Ch09.771 (empty folder), undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - AA04CH88.771 (empty folder), undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - AA04CH07.771 (empty folder), undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - AA04CH06, 1987 July 4 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - AA Chap. 5, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - AA05Ch10, 1985 July 28 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - AA03CH05.771, 1987 July 4 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - AA02CH04.771, 1987 July 4 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - AAPart00, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - AAPart06, 1987 July 4 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Shaping the Microelectronic Revolution to Serve True Development, 1984 Nov. 5 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - The World in A.D. 2000: Three Scenarios from Murray Thomson, 1980 Aug. 9 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Sector for Measuring Development Performance & Futures Studies, 1999 Nov. 14 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Using Ethnographic Futures Research in Development Work, 2000 Spring (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Redesigning the Roles of the Future Teacher: An Ethnographic Future Research (EFR), 2002 June 30 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Interviewing Reminder Sheet, Short Version, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - E.F.R. Interviewing Procedure Sheet, 2009 Feb. 11 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - E.F.R. Interviewing Procedure Sheet, 2009 Feb. 2 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Mail from Textor to Foulkes, 1992 Jan. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Thailand Futures Article - Critic's Comments, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Thomson, Murray, 1980 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Philips, Denis, 1973 Nov. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - General Release 4 Thai Consanguineal Kin, 1975 Jan. 16 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Makrakis, Vasilios, undated (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Stockholm Report, 1983-1985 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Riner, Reed, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Papaya Conference, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Tasks - AA Book, 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - International Development Research Centre, 1977 Nov. 28 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Purpose of Trip to Singapore and Indonesia, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Asia Trip 3 Report, 1978 Feb. 15 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Asia Trip 6- Log, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Ethnographic Futures Research as a Tool for Educational Diagnostics: A Brazilian case Study, 1979 Sept. (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Silicon Images: An Assessment of the Future Implications of the Computer Revolution, 1981 Nov. 4 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Shaping the Telemicroelectronic Revolution to Serve True Development, 1985 May 6 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Jia Protocol, 1979 April (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Anthropology Assignment for April 25, 1978 April 17 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Anthropology 269 Memo 1, 1978 April 10 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Wasp and Futures Article, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Chance Tasks, undated (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Some Models for Planning the Future, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Anticipatory Anthropology and the Telmicroelectronic Revolution: A Preliminary Report from Silicon Valley, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Osterreichische Book, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - World Future Review - Volume 27, 1995 May (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Futures - journal fo policy, planning and futures studies, 2000 October (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - EFRHNDBK - Notes 871, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - EMRC - Model: Impacts and Implications, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - EFRHNDBK - Front 871, 1987-1988 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - EDGE - German Study, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Asia Trip #9 - Trip Report, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Kuwait / Sa'ad English Translation (very partial), 1999 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Kuwait / Al-refai, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Proposal for an Anticipatory Anthropology Project, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - OSU Composite - Final, 2008 Feb 11 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - EFR Graphs, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - ERF Stanford - Old Drafts, 1987 May 23 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Possible Contributions of EFR, 1979 May 18 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Journal of Cultural and Educational Futures, 1979 April (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Ethnographic Futures Research and its Educational Potential, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Ethnographic Futuristics and the Future of Southeast Asian Studies, 1977 September (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - The Ortonville-Big Stone Future Study: Scientific Report, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - The Natural Partnership Between Ethnographic Futures Research and Futures Education, 1979 February (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Anthropology 69A EFR Reader, 1989 Winter (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - A Handbook on Ethnographic Research - Second Edition, Version C, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Anth 69A: Practicum in Ethnographic Futures Research, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - EFRE Handbook - Third Edition, Version A for Anth 269A, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Cultural Futures Research Journal, 1983 Spring (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Drug Education in the USA: A Possible Solution, 1990 May 21 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Student Research Papers, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Future Vision Report, 1995 March 4 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Materials for Write-Up - Salzburg, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Research Planning -- Long Range, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Catalyst - EFR Notes, undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Institute of International Education, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Report to the President of the Asia Foundation, 1981 Dec 15 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Anth 69 Memos, undated (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Anthropology 269 Textor Handbook, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Student Papers about Ethnography, 1990, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Clippings-Microelectronics, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - AA "Strengthening" AA, 1980 Oct 14 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - EFRHDBK\Chap 02 871, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - EFRHNDB\Chap 03 871, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - EFRHNDB\Chap 04 871, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - EFRHNDB\Chap 05 871, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - EHRC Prep Ch.2, 1985 Aug 17 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - EFRHNDB\Chap 01 871, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - AA01CH03. 771, 1985 Aug (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - AA01CH02. 771, 1985 Aug (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - AA01CH01. 771, 1985 Aug (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - AAPART00, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - AAPART00\Brandt, 881, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Kade Project, 2005 Dec 13 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Asia Trip 7 Keynote Speech, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Austria 2005- Reactions (Box 4, Folder 16)